### Siddhartha Prasad

siddhartha.a.prasad@gmail.com — sidprasad.github.io

I am a researcher focused on helping people write programs that behave as they intend. My research interests are informed by my time as an engineer. I have written code that doesn't do what I want it to, and I want to spare everyone else the indignity.

#### Education

Brown University, Providence, RI

Jan 2022 - Ongoing

PhD in Computer Science

Tufts University, Medford, MA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Mathematics

May 2016 Summa cum Laude High Thesis Honors

#### **Employment**

**Apple** 

Seattle, WA

Human-Centered Machine Learning team Research Intern

May - Sept 2023

Researcher on the team, exploring how AI and formal methods techniques can be used to support early childhood education.

Microsoft Redmond, WA April 2018 - Sept 2021

Software Engineer II

Applied AI team

- Developer on the Azure Cognitive Services team, that allow for AI to easily be injected into apps, bots, and websites.
- Built a containerized framework that allowed AI models to be run portably across a variety of operating systems and architectures.

Software Engineer

Developer Ecosystem team

Aug 2016 - March 2018

- Developed APIs and features for XAML, a UI language used by developers to build Universal Windows apps.
- Designed XAML APIs for input modalities (keyboard, gamepad, ink), accessibility, and cross-platform language support.

InternDeveloper Ecosystem team May - Aug 2015

**INRIA** Saclay, France Parsifal team Jun - July 2014 Intern

Research on correctness certificates for first order term-rewriting.

#### **Publications**

#### A Misconception-Driven Adaptive Tutor for Linear Temporal Logic

Siddhartha Prasad, Ben Greenman, Tim Nelson, Shriram Krishnamurthi

International Conference on Computer Aided Verification (CAV) [Distinguished Paper]

### Lightweight Diagramming for Lightweight Formal Methods: A Grounded Language Design

Siddhartha Prasad, Ben Greenman, Tim Nelson, Shriram Krishnamurthi

European Conference on Object-Oriented Programming (ECOOP) [Distinguished Paper] [Distinguished Artifact]

#### Misconceptions in Finite-Trace and Infinite-Trace Linear Temporal Logic 2024

Ben Greenman, Siddhartha Prasad, Antonio Di Stasio, Shufang Zhu, Giuseppe De Giacomo, Shriram Krishnamurthi, Marco Montali, Tim Nelson, Milda Zizyte

International Symposium on Formal Methods (FM)

#### ContextQ: Generated Questions to Support Meaningful Parent-Child Dialogue While Co-Reading

Griffin Dietz Smith, Siddhartha Prasad, Matt J Davidson, Leah Findlater, R Benjamin Shapiro Interaction Design and Children (IDC)

#### Forge: A Tool and Language for Teaching Formal Methods

Tim Nelson, Ben Greenman, Siddhartha Prasad, Tristan Dyer, Ethan Bove, Qianfan Chen, Charles Cutting, Thomas Del Vecchio, Sidney LeVine, Julianne Rudner, Ben Ryjikov, Alexander Varga, Andrew Wagner, Luke West, Shriram Krishnamurthi

#### OOPSLA (ACM SIGPLAN)

# 2024 Conceptual Mutation Testing for Student Programming Misconceptions Siddhartha Prasad, Ben Greenman, Tim Nelson, Shriram Krishnamurthi The Art, Science, and Engineering of Programming

# 2023 Generating Programs Trivially: Student Use of Large Language Models Siddhartha Prasad, Ben Greenman, Tim Nelson, Shriram Krishnamurthi ACM Conference on Global Computing Education (CompEd)

# 2022 Making Hay from Wheats: A Classsourcing Method to Identify Misconceptions Siddhartha Prasad, Ben Greenman, Tim Nelson, John Wrenn, Shriram Krishnamurthi Koli Calling International Conference on Computing Education Research

#### 2020 Large-Scale Intelligent Microservices

Mark Hamilton, Nick Gonsalves, Christina Lee, Anand Raman, Brendan Walsh, **Siddhartha Prasad**, Dalitso Banda, Lucy Zhang, Lei Zhang, William T Freeman

IEEE International Conference on Big Data